[The Ingenious One]
[Episode 5: Tumults in Nandu]
[Luo Family's Village]
It seems that those people will find you.
Are you scared?
You should be.
They will find you.
Are you scared?
You should be.
Luo Wenjia.
Did you have a nightmare?
No.
Wipe your sweat.
How long have I been asleep?
Are we almost there?
Yes.
[Jiang's Restaurant]
Tang Xiao's two guards
are indeed capable warriors.
The male guard is Zhong.
I've never seen him fight before,
so I don't know his specific fighting style.
But I think he's Japanese.
Why?
Last year,
some veterans from the government
smashed up one of the Tang family's shops.
They were found dead at the riverside that night.
Their swords were all cleaved.
The cuts on their armor were clean.
Those were typically caused by Japanese swordsmen.
Tang Xiao killed those soldiers.
How come no one was after him?
There was not enough evidence.
And Tang Xiao
has many connections in the government.
Therefore, the government killed several prisoners as scapegoats.
That's all.
What about the other guard?
She dresses quite differently from us.
Her name is Meizhu.
It is said that she was born in the far north.
I even fought with her once.
You?
This happened three years ago.
Back then, there was a man called Li Baiwan.
He was known as the best needle user.
He had a grudge against Tang Xiao,
so he summoned his men to fight Tang Xiao.
You don't like the story?
No, no. Continue.
Meizhu is good at using blunt weapons
and the method of martial arts she uses is unique.
Anyway,
she has something wrapped around her hands and arms.
Her attacking style is overbearing.
She's very strong.
But her movements are not sophisticated.
Even though she was attacked by a group of warriors,
she stayed unhurt.
How about Li Baiwan?
He went all out.
He used his Three Meteor Shower Moves.
Immediately, needles flew in the air, cutting raindrops and breaking stones,
just like the falling stars.
How did Meizhu react?
She just used her arms to cover her eyes.
She wasn't afraid of his needles at all.
Li Baiwan gave an evil grin.
He looked like a demon.
She's really a top warrior.
Without any hesitation, I used
my Wandering Step,
jumping off from three stories high.
She was so immersed in killing
and attacked me without any reason.
I used the Dragon Sword to dissolve her momentum.
I was not afraid of her at all.
Anyway,
if you don't fight with her yourself,
you won't understand how strong she is.
You can't figure it out by only watching.
If you consider that as "fighting with her",
I can brag I conquered the martial world.
At least I had a combat with her.
Then,
how will you compare Meizhu and Zhong
to Qi Tianfeng?
Qi Tianfeng?
He's really a top martial artist.
He's known as the Iron Hand Demon.
His Twelve Wave-breaking Palms are almost invincible in Nandu.
But all these years of fighting
left him injured.
I've never heard him fight with anyone again.
Why are you asking about Qi Tianfeng?
Qi Tianfeng is famous.
By comparing your fight with Meizhu
and your fight with Qi Tianfeng,
Miss Shu can know how good you are.
If I want to fight with Qi Tianfeng,
I have to practice for a few more years.
According to what you just said,
Tang Xiao has always been unruly.
We bought Liansheng House.
Won't he hate us?
Don't worry.
No matter how arrogant Tang Xiao is,
he doesn't dare to provoke the Su family,
let alone my friends.
Friends? That's very nice of you.
Sir.
Here.
We had some misunderstandings.
But now I know you are a righteous man.
Although you don't know martial arts, you have a warrior's heart.
Here.
That's enough.
Cut the crap.
Let's get down to business.
That's right.
How can I forget such an important thing?
Mr. Yun,
I've handed my 3,000 taels to the Chamber of Commerce.
When you fill in the other 3,000 taels,
we can get the deed.
What's the deadline for that?
What do you mean?
Can't you understand?
Does he look like he's rich?
I'm just asking about the time.
As stipulated by the Chamber of Commerce,
all procedures should be done before five.
The deal will be canceled after five o'clock
and the already paid-in will not be returned.
Five o'clock.
It's already past one now.
Only four hours left.
Do you have 3,000 taels?
I'm paid to protect him.
Please forgive me.
There are still four hours left.
Mr. Su,
don't jump to conclusions.
There are only four hours left.
How can I trust you?
You don't have other choices now.
Mr. Su, please calm down.
You can take a rest in the Chamber of Commerce.
I will get the money
and send it to the Chamber of Commerce in time.
Okay, I'll wait for you.
Waiter.
I have a task for you.
I'll tell you a place.
Send the food on the table and this
to that place.
Okay, thank you.
Su Mingyu
talked a good game about martial arts,
but he's just a lightweight.
I tried him just now.
He immediately flinched.
He's just like you.
Only 30% of what you say is true.
30%?
I'd say you think too highly of me.
None of you is completely honest.
How about this?
We terminate our agreement.
I'll take a few orders to make some money.
Then I'll pay you back, okay?
Will you leave
when you complete your revenge?
Of course.
What's wrong?
Nothing. I was just asking.
Every sentence you say
has a purpose.
What?
Come here.
What do you want to do?
Don't mention Qi Tianfeng
in front of Su Mingyu again.
I can see you intentionally interrupted me.
But I don't know why.
Think about this. Meizhu once fought Su Mingyu.
Why didn't Tang Xiao, who is so unruly,
kill Su Mingyu?
He must be afraid of the Su family's status.
Yes.
What else did you notice
during the auction?
Although Tang Xiao was humiliated,
he didn't offend Su Mingyu.
It can be seen that the Su family has a high status.
So, we are not only using Su Mingyu
to help us cross the river.
I didn't want to say this.
But I'm really afraid that you'll be too impatient
and let the cat out of the bag.
But thanks to my question,
at least I know that Qi Tianfeng is suffering from old injuries
and he's not as powerful as he used to be.
Using force is not the only way to achieve revenge.
At this point, I can tell you
I'm only one step away
from finishing my plan.
Trust me.
Get the 3,000 taels
in four hours first.
Sit back.
You sit over there.
I want to show you something.
It's very important.
We're here.
[Guanghui Bank]
Wait here for a moment.
Godfather is gone.
You want to get 3,000 taels
with those invoices?
Maybe. Maybe not.
So mysterious. I don't believe you can.
I think he just wants to buy time.
It's a mere formality.
Jin.
You wanna bet?
Bet?
On what?
If I can't get 3,000 taels
within two hours,
you and I will be even.
Don't fall for his trick.
Do you have money deposited here?
No.
Do you have any mortgageable property?
You know any rich men in Nandu?
Only one. Su Mingyu.
Fine.
If you get 3,000 taels,
I'll work for you for several more months.
If you can't,
we'll be even.
Deal.
Don't shake your head for him.
You ask me for 3,000 taels of silver
with these old papers?
Ridiculous!
Mr. Wen is gone.
His assets should belong to Yuntai Sect.
But most of them
are now in your hands.
What do you think Master will do
if he knows about this?
Mr. Mo,
even if you've only taken back
70% of the loans Mr. Wen gave out,
that's tens of thousands of taels.
Even if I have tens of millions of taels,
it has nothing to do with you.
You came to Nandu without permission
and intervened in Wen Cong's affairs.
Yun Xiang.
I don't want to make you look bad
because you're Master's direct disciple.
Without permission?
Does that mean I need your permission
to come to Nandu?
Master asked you to take care of things in Yuezhou.
He never sent you here to make Wen Cong your business.
You're really well-informed.
Yun Xiang.
I'm being nice.
Don't push your luck.
Are you trying to blackmail me?
Behave yourself.
If I don't give you the 3,000 taels,
will you report me to Master,
accusing me of embezzlement?
Are you going to say I'm looking on
when Master's property is at risk?
Brat.
I've been working hard for the sect
in Nandu for many years.
So what if you're Master's direct disciple?
You can't say Master trust me or you more.
Let's each write a letter to him
and see who he trusts.
Why are you smiling?
Mr. Mo, you and I are the same kind of people.
I want power and you want money.
I already know your intention.
What's that about?
A 5% monthly interest rate.
I borrow 3,000 taels from you
at an interest rate of 5%.
I'll pay you back in a month.
What about 10%?
I can see you're truly desperate.
Even 10% is not intriguing enough to you?
How about this?
For every tael I borrow, I'll pay you ten back.
If I can't pay you back within a month,
I'm at your disposal.
Why hasn't he come out yet?
We can take bets as well. What do you think?
I don't think you stand a chance.
I didn't expect to part ways with you so suddenly.
Goodbye, Yun Xiang.
Are you really leaving?
A bet is a bet.
See you.
If you leave,
I'll be in danger without your protection.
You still have Shu Yanan.
Jin,
you are the real hero
in my heart.
Well...
Mr. Yun.
This is from Mr. Mo.
You don't want to leave me, right?
Seeing you shaking your head is annoying.
Bite me!
Mr. Mo of Guanghui Bank is also on your side?
That's not what matters.
What matters is that it's a money house.
Did you borrow the money?
You have assets that can be mortgaged?
I promised to pay ten times back.
What else should I mortgage?
Ten times?
That means you have to repay 30,000 taels.
In a month
You are too bold.
I just want to make it quick.
Tell me what your next move is.
There's something I need your help with.
Uncle, it's true that
some of Wen Cong's debt has been paid.
But I remember
because of the money he owed us back then,
you almost closed your business.
Why didn't you tell Yun Xiang about this?
Would it help?
Would he believe it?
Yun Xiang bought Liansheng House with six thousand taels.
To pay for that, he promised to pay you ten times back.
He is really strange.
Anyway,
if he repays 30,000 taels as promised,
it will be an unexpected fortune.
What if he can't pay it back?
Will he really leave Nandu?
I can't see through him yet.
But after this,
we can't be friends.
That's all.
Okay.
After you go back,
thank Warrior Jin for me.
Thank you for your trouble.
We won't walk you out then.
May I use the toilet?
Isn't there supposed to be more than ten kids?
Uncle.
Please take me with you.
Little girl,
what's wrong with you?
So troublesome.
Dear.
I don't think Jin Biao
will leave Nandu soon.
It will be a problem if someone else comes again.
Let's leave then.
We can do our business anywhere.
Coward!
Even if we run away from Jin Biao today,
there is always someone else after us.
Then should we keep running?
It's not the first time that
a swordsman has targeted us.
[Nandu Chamber of Commerce]
Who knows how long he'll be in there.
Why don't you take a rest in the carriage?
I'll find a place to drink.
You wait here.
I have something to do.
I've counted all the six thousand taels.
This is the deed of Liansheng House.
Please have a look.
If there is no problem,
you can sign it.
Qian, please stamp the official seal of the Chamber of Commerce.
Then come with me to the room inside.
The chairman is waiting for you too.
It's done.
Sister,
you look thinner.
You've been avoiding me
since you came back from Yangzhou.
Liansheng House is not worth 6,000 taels.
I know that. But...
Let's not talk about this.
Mingyu,
are you serious about that girl?
You insisted on buying Liansheng House
because you want to give that girl
a place to stay?
Yes. I mean it.
I only care about her.
I'm a commoner and she's not. Our marriage is not allowed.
I'll find a way to make her a commoner.
It's not an easy thing.
What do you plan to do now?
For now, I can only keep her from being bullied by Tang Xiao.
No other specific plans have been made.
I can help you.
Are you okay with it?
I've been strict with you
because I worried it's just a spur-of-the-moment thing to you.
But I've seen what you did in the past two years.
It's a good thing if you have someone in your heart.
It would be a pity
if you can't spend more time together
just because of differences in social status.
But you have to promise me one thing.
What is it?
I can help Miss Ke to be a commoner.
But you need to learn to do business.
Because in the future,
you have to take care of the business of our family.
[Liansheng House]
Mr. Su.
You're home.
You bought Liansheng House as you wished.
You can win her heart with that. Why are you unhappy?
Don't you like her anymore because you've got what you want?
If that's the case,
I'll...
You two gentlemen have saved Liansheng House.
I thank you on behalf of all the girls.
Mr. Yun, you are an amazing gambler.
I'm glad you are the new owner of Liansheng House.
I'm flattered.
Menglan.
I don't know how to thank you.
I prepared some wine.
Please go upstairs and enjoy.
Am I invited too?
Of course.
Miss Ke,
this is now my place as well.
You don't have to follow me.
I want to show Jin around.
Please go ahead.
Go.
I have something to tell you.
Please.
Menglan. Menglan.
Why are you not as close to me as before?
If I made you misunderstand in the past,
it was my fault.
I thank you very much
for buying Liansheng House.
I'll do my best to work for you in the future.
That's all.
I hope you can understand.
Why?
Why are you confused?
If some Mr. Zhang or Mr. Liu bought this place,
should I offer myself as well?
Is this a business regulation
or any unspoken rule?
But I'm not them.
Menglan.
I never asked you before.
I'll ask you only once.
Do you like me?
Love in the world, in very rare cases,
is as firm as a rock.
Most of the time, it's like a floating cloud.
Don't bother yourself with it.
Menglan.
You don't have to trust others.
But can you trust me?
Please let go of me.
Miss Shu.
You're back.
I'll go with you.
We accidentally entered that inn.
There were soldiers outside and bandits inside.
It was a mess. Sabers, swords, and arrows.
But with your martial skills,
you should be able to get out.
Of course.
But the two young men who were with me couldn't.
We were there together.
How could I escape on my own?
Right?
Here, fill it up for me.
I'm captivated by the story. Sorry.
It doesn't matter.
I told them,
"Guys,
there's only one way out today.
Let's swim out of this latrine."
Then we swam out.
What are you talking about?
If it's a joke, tell it again.
Perfect timing.
Jin is sharing one of his experiences.
-He once... -Shut up.
How can you tell this to Miss Ke?
It's too rude for girls.
I don't know what kind of joke it is,
but this is the first time
that I have seen Tianhu smile like this.
Miss Ke,
this toast is for you.
We hit it off.
I'll help you
if anyone comes to make trouble.
Thank you.
With Mr. Yun as the owner of Liansheng House,
I'm sure everything will go smoothly in the future.
Cheers.
The dulcet music and the bright moon.
How beautiful!
Such scenery is priceless.
A wonderful picture on such a lovely night.
But it seems to be a pity
without a beauty by your side.
You're wrong.
You said it
in a too flippant manner.
There are so many injustices in the world.
Sad love life is not a big deal.
I feel sad for you, in fact.
Look at you.
You don't have...
Your heart is stone.
Do you know
why Miss Ke is keeping a distance from you?
You're not an open-hearted person.
You have so many secrets.
But there are things only you can see through.
Maybe I can even provide solutions.
I do have one thing on my mind.
Can you keep it a secret for me?
My sister is willing to help Menglan be a commoner.
She also agreed that I can marry Menglan.
Under what conditions?
She asked me to learn to do business
and take over the family business.
This problem can be solved.
Can you
help Menglan change her status
without the help of my sister?
To do that, you need connections in the Music Department.
As the big boss of the gambling industry in Nandu,
Tang Xiao definitely has the connections you want.
You want to ask Tang Xiao for help?
You're walking straight into a lion's den.
He wanted Menglan to be his concubine
if he made Menglan a commoner.
The conditions are negotiable.
Mr. Su.
If you trust me,
why don't you leave it to me?
[Cao Sect]
[Su's Silk Warehouse]
[Yufeng Warehouse]
Here.
Fire! Fire!
Help!
Actually, I've come up with an idea.
But I still need an opportunity.
Flames there are shooting up.
There seems to be a lot of flammable things.
This direction...
That's my family's silk warehouse.